Okay, so, let's talk about this problem of predicting the value of a house.
주택 가치 예측 문제에 대해 알아보죠
So, this is a very important problem, at least in the United States.
아주 중요한 문제입니다 적어도 미국에서는요
It's estimated that household wealth is nearly 50% invested in real estate.
가계자산의 50% 가깝게 부동산에 투자돼있다고 예측됩니다
So, this is clearly important.
소비자와 개인, 정부에게
Both to consumers, individuals, as well as policy makers.
분명히 중요합니다
Okay, so I'm here and I wanna sell my house.
제가 집을 팔고 싶다고 하죠
I have this nice, big, lime green house, but I don't know how much to list it for.
크고 예쁘며 푸른 집을 갖고 있는데 얼마에 내놔야 할지 모릅니다
So I'm not sure what value my house has, and so
주택 가치가 어느 정도인지 잘 모르겠습니다
how do I think about estimating the value of the house?
가치 예측에 어떻게 접근해야 할까요?
Well, it might make sense that what I do is I look
우선 인근 주택들의 최근 판매 가격을
at other recent sales that have occurred in my neighborhood.
살펴보는 것도 방법이겠죠
So I look locally, at the region around me, and
근처 지역을 둘러보며 다른 집들은
I say how much are the other houses sold for and what do those houses look like?
얼마에 팔렸는지 생김새는 어떤지 봅니다
So what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna record for
그리고 최근 판매 기록을 보며
each one of these recent sales what was the sales price?
가격은 얼마였는지
And also, what was the size of the house that was sold?
크기는 어떠했는지 봅니다
I'm gonna say that that's what signifies whether that house is similar to mine
이 두 기준으로 대상 주택이 제 집과
or not.
비슷한지 아닌지를 판별합니다
Okay, so being a statistician, I'm gonna take all these observations I had and
통계학자이니 모든 관찰 결과를
I'm gonna make a plot of them.
그래프로 나타내 보겠습니다
So in the US at least, the size of the house is measured by square feet.
미국에서는 주택 크기를 평방 피트로 측정합니다
So that's gonna be my x axis.
이걸 x축으로 삼고요
And then my y axis is gonna be the sales price of the house.
y축은 주택 판매 가격이 됩니다
Okay, so that's my y variable and
y 변수는 그렇고
each one of these points represents some individual house sale.
이 각각의 점은 특정 주택 가격을 나타냅니다
So here this is one previous house sale in my neighborhood.
여기 이건 인근 주택의 판매 가격이죠
And just to introduce a little bit of terminology here when we're
용어를 살짝 소개하자면
talking about regression, people often refer to x, this variable x,
회귀에서 변수 x는
as being the feature, that's the terminology we've been using.
저희가 계속 말해왔듯이 특징인데
People also talk about it being the covariate or the predictor,
공변량이나 예측변수라고도 부릅니다
and in some cases, it's called the independent variable.
어떤 때는 독립변수라고 하지요
And then our observation y is as I've just said,
관찰 결과 y는 제가 말했듯이
I tend to refer to it as an observation.
저는 주로 관찰 결과라고 지칭합니다
People also call it a response or the dependent variable.
응답변수나 종속변수라고도 부릅니다
Okay, so
이제
the question is how am I gonna use these observations to estimate my house value?
이 관찰 결과를 놓고 저희 집의 가치를 어떻게 예측할까요?
Well I might look at how big my house is and
저희 집이 얼마나 큰지 보고
look for other sales of houses of that size.
같은 크기 집의 판매 기록을 찾습니다
Well, most likely there are gonna be exactly zero house
평수가 정확히 같은 집은
sales of other houses that had exactly the same square footage as my house.
하나도 없을 가능성이 높죠
Okay, so I say well I can't use this approach.
이런 접근은 어렵습니다
I'm gonna be a little bit more flexible and
유연성을 발휘해서
I'm gonna look at some neighborhood, not geographic neighborhood some little range
이웃, 그러니까 지역적으로 이웃이 아니라
of square footage around my actual square footage here.
평수가 비슷한 집들을 찾습니다
So I'm going to say okay let's look at all house sales that were for
이 평수 범위 안에 있는
houses within this range of square footage.
주택 가격을 조사해 보는 거죠
But even with that approach, in this case for example,
하지만 이렇게 접근해도
I only have two house sales that I'm gonna base my estimate off of.
예측의 기반이 되는 판매 기록은 두 개밖에 없습니다
So I don't really feel very comfortable with that.
이걸론 충분하지 않을 것 같죠
And what I'm actually doing here is I'm throwing out all these other observations
그리고 지금 다른 모든 관찰 결과는
as if they had nothing to do with the value of my house.
주택 가치와 상관이 없다고 상정하고 있죠
And the question is, is that reasonable?
정말 그런가요?
Do we actually believe that there's actually no information
이 관결 결과에 아무런 정보도 없다고
in these other observations?
단정할 수 있나요?
Well, when I look at this data and when I think about data I like to leverage all
저는 이 데이터에서 얻을 수 있는
the information that I can to come up with good predictions.
모든 정보가 예측에 반영되기를 바랍니다